Peter Fonda is riding again... To the woman he
lost... for the revenge he craves!
The Hired Hand is a western film directed by Peter Fonda.
Harry Collings returns home to his farm after drifting with his friend, Arch.
His wife, who had given up on him, reluctantly allows him to
stay, and soon believes that all will be well again.
But then Harry has to make a difficult decision
regarding his loyalties and priorities.
Harry Collings, played by Peter Fonda.
Arch Harris, played by Warren Oates.
Hannah Collings, played by Verna Bloom.
Dan Griffen, played by Robert Pratt.
McVey, played by Severn Darden.
Mexican Woman, played by Rita Rogers.
The Hired Hand is a 1971 American Western film directed by
Peter Fonda, with a screenplay by Alan Sharp.
The film stars Fonda, Warren Oates, and Verna Bloom.
The cinematography was by Vilmos Zsigmond.
Bruce Langhorne provided the moody film score.
The story is about a man returning to his abandoned wife after seven years of
drifting from job to job throughout the Southwestern United States.
The embittered woman will only let him stay if he
agrees to move in as a hired hand.
Upon release, the film received a mixed critical
response and was a financial failure.
In 1973, the film was shown on NBC-TV in an expanded
version, but soon drifted into obscurity.
In 2001, a fully restored version was shown at various film festivals, gaining strong
critical praise, and it was released by the Sundance Channel on DVD.
It is now considered a classic Western of the period.